Vu Hoang Vu

Contact

(318) 658-0335 vuvuhoang99@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/vu-vu-694458159

Overview

Vu Hoang Vu has professional experience in Petrochemical, Life Sciences, Pulp and Paper, and Process Automation. He has experience in implementation of continuous and batch control strategies along with documentation.

System Experience

- DeltaV
- Studio 5000
- Honeywell TDC 3000
- Triconex
- Honeywell Experion
- AutoCAD

Education

B.S., Electrical Engineering, Louisiana Tech University

Certifications

- E.I.T
- Emerson 7409 DeltaV Implementation I with DeltaV live
- Emerson 7016 DeltaV System Batch Implementation

Work Experience

R.E. Mason, Durham, NC Systems Engineer June 2021 – Current

DeltaV Consultant, Novo Nordisk (Contractor)

- Configured control modules, equipment modules, and recipe for CIP in fermentation and recovery process unit
- Configured graphic changes on DeltaV Operate
- Tune PID controller and valves
- Assists process engineers in making automation changes for FDA approval
- Document changes in Functional Specification
- Support 2nd shift for CIP development
- Assist in training new automation support technicians in DeltaV

Calumet Specialty Products, Shreveport, LA Control System Engineer Intern June 2020 – February 2021

- Developed an Instruments Index as a basis for instrumentation scope for DCS migration and for future SPI implementation
- Developed a LCN and UCN network map for the Honeywell DCS
- Manage an installation project of flow meters, totalizer, and MOV
 - Create a program on Studio 5000 to bring the reading across Modbus into TDC 3000 and OSI PI ProcessBook
 - o Modify graphics on TDC 3000
 - Create logic blocks diagram for the MOV
- Support operation for startup of the refinery
- Support E/I technicians and contractors for installation for new instruments
- Perform PM for Honeywell, Triconex, Allen Bradley, and RTP SIS system
- Assist control engineers in planning for the turnaround

Clearwater Paper Corporation, McGehee, AR Electrical Reliability Engineer Intern May 2019 – August 2019

- Implemented preventative maintenance strategies
- Applied weekly predictive maintenance: infrared thermography and vibration analysis
- Assessed motor health and applied hands-on field troubleshooting
- Installed C300 controller and configure analog points for temperature transmitter
- Update electrical schematics, P&ID, and Loop drawings
- Collaborate with contractor to establish the Emerson AMS system